Patrick Trollip

Full-Stack Developer

ptrollip@gmail.com

0862454647

Cherry Blossom cottage,

Dunboyne Gate lodge,
Maynooth, County Kildare. W23
E7K8.

Web development collaboration prize for a hackathon.

Excellent security knowledge and knowledge of cyber security threats.

Prepared to learn more and improve and add more value to my IT career.

Skills

| - 4 | \/\/oh | daval | opment |
|-----|--------|-------|---------|
| | VVCD | uevei | Opinent |

Locksmith

Soft skills

Security knowledge

General it knowledge

English language

Intermediate level in german

Portuguese

Leadership

Communication

Teamwork

Time management

Problem solving

📭 Software

Html and css

Javascript

Python programming

Git Bash

Angularjs

Windows os

Visual studio code

Vm virtual box

Command line

Chrome developer tools

🔁 Languages

English language



























- German
- Portuguese





Hobby

My interest inculde learning new skills, improving my current skill base like building Javascript games for experience and fun.

Health and fitness like practicing body weight exercises for general health and improved cognitive preformance.

Locksport: It involves tool making, lock manipulation and decoding, problem solving, building locks, sharing locks with the community and teaching others about locks and security so they can make informed choices on their security needs.

Volunteering with first aid duties when I have the time.

Martial arts: Kickboxing and BJJ.

Coding on my own.

Spending time with friends and family.

Staying goal focused and being productive.

요

Education

Code institute, Dublin

Diploma, Full stack web development

IT Career switch, Dublin

Full stack engineer, Web development

• DFEI, Dublin

FETAC 6, Security Business Admin

Newpark Comprehensive school, Dublin

Leaving cert, Secondary school

Work History

Security Officer

MCR, Dublin

I do a wide range of security duties and IT admin tasks.

It involves problem solving, attention to detail, customer service, dealing with the public, working in a fast paced environment to name a few tasks.

Patrol Driver

Bidvest Noonan, Dublin

Working on my own initiative to meet dealines and client expectations.

Alarm response and key holding.

Opening premises and lock ups.

Other security duties.

2019-03 - 2020-07

2011-09 - 2013-05

2020-09 - present

2004-09 - 2010-06

2020-08 - present

2018-11 - 2020-08

2019-05 - 2019-06

2019-07 - 2019-08



Projects

Milestone 1

I was the front end developer

I had to build a website for a band that wanted to be able to connect with their fans online via social media and advertise their events.

I used HTML, CSS and JAvascript.

It was my first project on my own.

Farmer vs Aliens

Front end developer

I built a Javascript game for my milestone project that was a simple side scrolling game that used the Canvas in HTML to build a interactive game. It was my first game I built.

Tennis

Student project

I built a game through a Udemy tutorial to practice my Javascript coding.

The game is a recreation of the classic game PONG.

I is a single player game that has a AI player that hits a ball element back at you.

The difficulty and all can be updated as the code is a little modular for easy maintenance.

Volunteering

Irish Cancer Society

Volunteering in the charity shop as a volunteer store assistant.

Irish red cross

Volunteer First aider at events big and small in Dublin.

Courses

Security studies

Fetac 5 security course.

Security Business admin

Fetac 6 course.

Diploma in criminology

Course done through City Colleges.

Intruder Alarms and access control

FETAC 5 module course.

Locksmithing

FETAC 4 Locksmithing course done with Train Locksmiths in Manchester.

Full stack web development

Course done through Code institute.

Web engineer

Completing this course through IT career switch.

Certificates

Diploma in Full stack Web development

I covered front end technologies like HTML, CSS and Javascript and some frameworks.

2019-11 - 2019-11

2011-12 - 2012-06

2012-04 - 2013-04

I covered data bases and back end technologies like Pyhthon, SQL llte, Mongo DB, AWS S3, Heroku, Travis testing framework.

I built a number of milestone projects and I collaborated with fellow students and we won first prize for the October Hackathon together.

Diploma in Criminology and Criminal psychology(Police)

I did a part time diploma with City colleges in Dublin to learn about how criminals opperate and how they think and their heirarchy.

Locksmithing

I learnt how to be a locksmith in Manchester with Master locksmiths from Train Locksmiths. It involved lock installs, entry methods both no destructive, key making, picking locks, installing locks and fitting locks. Car openings and key making.

IT career switch

I am currently furthering my knowledge and understanding of Web development through IT career switch and will graduate in 2021.

It involves furthering my experience in technologies I learnt at code institute and learning new technologies like Java and reactJS for example.

References

Adrian Parker

Security manager, Bidvest Noonan

Alan Lynsky

Security Manager, MCR group

Carl Whelan

Supervisor, MCR group

Paul Dowling

Chief instructor, Rathdown Kenpo Karate